American Trust for the British Library Project Master Negatives on Microfilm 6060 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Trust for the British Library Project Master Negatives on Microfilm
1889-1954
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Trust for the British Library
6060 mf
0.56 cubic feet
5 microfilm reels
Records, microfilm.
5771288
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 02, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 18, 2015
Biographical / Historical
The American Trust for the British Library is a not-for-profit organization whose purpose is to promote and support the work of one of the world's greatest research libraries. The Trust was founded in 1979 and is supported through the generosity of its wide membership in the United States and the United Kingdom.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
American Trust for the British Library
5771288
- LB 1 Ebert, Justus American industrial evolution from the frontier to the factory (1907), 1 (Reel 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Master negative
- LB 5 Merritt, Walter G. Destination unknown (1951), 2 (Reel 1)
  Master Negative
- LB 6 Federal Writers' Project, New York (N.Y.) A trial bibliography of bibliographies (1937), 3 (Reel 1)
- LB 27 Browne, Waldo R. comp. What's what in the labor movement (1921), 4 (Reel 1)
- LB 31 Hardman, J.B.S. American labor dynamics in the light of post-war developments (1928), 5 (Reel 1)
- LB 33 Laidler, Harry W. Prosperity? Symposium by Stuart Chase (1927), 6 (Reel 1)
- LB 35 Ladler, Harry W. and Norman M. Thomas, eds. New tactics in social conflict (1926), 7 (Reel 1)
- LB 26 Williams, Whiting What's on the worker's mind (1920), 8 (Reel 1)
- LB 37 Pound, Arthur The iron man in industry (1922), 9 (Reel 1)
- LB 38 Princeton University. Industrial Relations Section The labor banking movement (1929), 10 (Reel 1)
- LB 39 Gordon, Manya How to tell progress from reaction (1944), 11 (Reel 1)
- LB 41 Keir, Robert M. Labor problems from both sides (1938), 12 (Reel 1)
- LB 44 National Industrial Conference Board. Effect of the depression on industrial relations programs (1934), 13 (Reel 1)
- LB 45 National Industrial Conference Board Individual and collective bargaining (1933), 14 (Reel 1)
- LB 47 Rector, Harvey B. How to build independent unions under new deal legislation (1942 ), 15 (Reel 1)
- LB 51 Schlossberg, Joseph The workers and their world (1935), 16 (Reel 1)
- LB 54 Thomas, Norman M. Human exploitation in the United States (1934), 17 (Reel 1)
  Master Negatives
- LB 55 Adams, Leonard P. Wartime manpower mobilization (1951), 18 (Reel 1)
- LB 56 Labor and nation. V.1-8 (no. 1-33) (1945-1952) [v.1and2], 19 (Reel 1)
- LB 56 Labor and nation v.1-8 (no.1-33)(1945-1952) [v.3], 20 (Reel 1)
- LB 56 Labor and nation. V1-8 (no.1-33) [1945-1952] [v.4], 21 (Reel 1)
- LB 56 Labor and nation. V.1-8 (no.1-33) [1945-1952] vol.6, 22 (Reel 1)
  Maser Negative
- LB 56 Labor and nation. V.1-8 (no.1-33) [1945-1952] vol.5, 23 (Reel 1)
- LB 56 Labor and nation. V1-8 (no.1-33) [1945-1952] -- vol. 7-8, 24 (Reel 1)
- LB 57 Lens, Sidney Left, right, and center (1949), 25 (Reel 1)
- LB 59 Levenstein, Aaron Labor today and tomorrow (1945), 26 (Reel 1)
- LB 60 Millholland, Ray Pay day: labor and management in the American system of free enterprise (1946), 27 (Reel 1)
- LB 61 Riegelman, Carol Labour-management co-operation in United States war production (1948), 28 (Reel 1)
- LB 63 Stewart, Bryce M. and Walter J. Couper Maintenance of union membership (1943), 29 (Reel 1)
- LB 69 -- Tippett, Thomas When Southern labor stirs (1931), 30 (Reel 1)
- LB 70 Anson, Charles P. A history of labor movement (1940), 31 (Reel 1)
- LB 73 Byrnes, Agnes M. H. Industrial homework (1923), 32 (Reel 1)
- LB 74 Carr, Charlotte E. Labor and industry in the depression (1934), 33 (Reel 1)
- LB 6 Federal Writers' Project, New York (N.Y.) A trial bibliography of bibliographies (1937) [2nd film], 34 (Reel 1)
- LB 31 Hardman, J.B.S. American labor dynamics in the light of post-war developments (1928) [2nd copy], 35 (Reel 1)
- LB 83 Cale, Edgar B. The organization of labor in Philadelphia (1940), 1 (Reel 2)
- LB 85 -- Hardwick, A.F. History of the Central Labor Union of Springfield, Mass., with some of the pioneers (1912), 2 (Reel 2)
- LB 86 Lowe, Boutelle E. Representative industry and trade unionism of an American city (1912), 3 (Reel 2)
- LB 76 Heintz, Albert M. and John R. Whitney History of the Massachusetts State Federation of Labor (1935), 4 (Reel 2)
- LB 90 Budenz, Louis This is my story (1947), 5 (Reel 2)
- LB 100 Bransten, Richard and John Stuart Men who lead labor (1937), 6 (Reel 2)
- LB 110 Karsner, David Talks with Debs in Terre Haute and letters from Lindlahr (1922), 7 (Reel 2)
- LB 111 Newspaper Guild of N.Y. Heywood Broun as he seemed to us (1940), 8 (Reel 2)
- LB 112 Painter, Floy R. That man Debs and his life work (1929), 9 (Reel 2)
- LB 114 Petersen, Arnold. Daniel DeLeon: social architect (1941-1953) [v.1], 10 (Reel 2)
- LB 114 Petersen, Arnold Daniel DeLeon: social architect (1941-1953) [v.2], 11 (Reel 2)
- LB 122 Bowers, Edison L. Is it safe to work? (1930), 12 (Reel 2)
- LB 125 Feis, Herbert, ed. A collection of decisions presenting principles of wage settlement (1924), 13 (Reel 2)
- LB 128 Henderson, Charles R. Industrial insurance in the United States (1909), 14 (Reel 2)
- LB 129 Husslein, Joseph C. Work, wealth and wages (1921), 15 (Reel 2)
- LB 130 Johnsen, Julia E. The closed shop (1942), 16 (Reel 2)
- LB 134 Latimer, Murray W. and Carl Tufel Trends in industrial pensions (1940), 17 (Reel 2)
- LB 141 Riegel, John W. Management, labor and technological change (1942), 18 (Reel 2)
- LB 144 Calkins, Clinch M. Some folks won't work. (1930), 19 (Reel 2)
- LB 145 Clague, Ewan, Walter J. Couper, and E.Wight Bakke After the shutdown (1934), 20 (Reel 2)
- LB 146 Clague, Ewan, and Webster Powell Ten thousand out of work (1933), 21 (Reel 2)
- LB 149 Hopkins, Jess T., et. Al The emergence of a new public employment service (1935), 22 (Reel 2)
- LB 152 Lewisohn, Sam A. Et al. Can business prevent unemployment? (1925), 23 (Reel 2)
- LB 154 -- Lubin, Isador. The absorption of the unemployed by American industry. Washington, DC: Brookings Institution, (1929), 24 (Reel 2)
- LB 155 Myers, Charles A. and W. Rupert MacLaurin The movement of factory workers (1943), 25 (Reel 2)
- LB 158 Stewart, Bryce M. Planning and administration of unemployment (1938), 26 (Reel 2)
- LB 160 Gleason, Arthur H. Workers' education (1921), 27 (Reel 2)
- LB 160 Gleason, Arthur H. Workers' education (1921) [2nd copy], 28 (Reel 2)
- LB 163 Lutz, Rufus R. Wage earning and education (1916), 29 (Reel 2)
- LB 170 Ware, Caroline F. Labor education in universities (1946), 30 (Reel 2)
- LB 181 Nestor, Agnes Woman's labor leader (1954), 31 (Reel 2)
- LB 184 Pruette, Lorine, ed. Women workers through the depression (1934), 32 (Reel 2)
- LB 192 Patkin, A.L. The origin of the Russian-Jewish labor movement (1947), 33 (Reel 2)
- LB 193 Hayes, Laurence J.W. The Negro federal government worker (1941), 34 (Reel 2)
- LB 197 Scott, Estelle Hill Occupational changes among Negroes in Chicago (1939), 35 (Reel 2)
- LB 210 U.S. Children's Bureau. Child labor legislation in the United States. (1915), 36 (Reel 2)
- LB 221 Broderick, John T. Pulling together (1922), 37 (Reel 2)
- LB 229 Lange, Frederick Charles The industrial crisis (1903), 1 (Reel 3)
- LB 248 National Conference on the Christian Way of Life The question of recognizing the union (1924), 2 (Reel 3)
- LB 256 Delaney, Ed and M.T. Rice The bloodstained trail (1927), 3 (Reel 3)
- LB 259 Holmes, John H. Is violence the way out of our industrial disputes? (1920), 4 (Reel 3)
- LB 262 McLean, Donald A. The morality of the strike (1921), 5 (Reel 3)
- LB 265 The Mooney-Billings report (1932), 6 (Reel 3)
- LB 265 The Mooney-Billings report (1932) [2nd copy], 7 (Reel 3)
- LB 266 Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues Industrial conflict: a psychological interpretation (1939), 8 (Reel 3)
- LB 267 Spielman, Jean E. The stool-pigeon and the open shop movement (1923), 9 (Reel 3)
- LB 268 Steuben, John Strike strategy (1950), 10 (Reel 3)
- LB 270 Trautmann, William E. and Peter Hagboldt Riot. (1922), 11 (Reel 3)
- LB 276 Myers, James Representative government in industry (1924), 12 (Reel 3)
- LB 277 Nichols, Egbert R. and James W. Logan Arbitration and the National Labor Relations Board (1937), 13 (Reel 3)
- LB 278 Nichols, Osgood and Thomas R. Carskadon Can labor and management work together? (1949), 14 (Reel 3)
- LB 279 Soule, George Henry Wage arbitration, selected cases, 1920-1924 (1928), 15 (Reel 3)
- LB 280 Weinfeld, Abraham Chaim Labor treaties and labor compacts (1937), 16 (Reel 3)
- LB 281 Roe, Wellington Juggernaut: American labor in action (1948), 17 (Reel 3)
- LB 284 Sullivan, Edward D. This labor union racket (1936), 18 (Reel 3)
- LB 285 Tannenbaum, Frank A philosophy of labor (1951), 19 (Reel 3)
- LB 290 Robbins, Hayes The labor movement and the farmer (1922), 20 (Reel 3)
- LB 293 Hodgson, James G., comp. A labor party for the United States (1925), 21 (Reel 3)
- LB 303 De Leon, Daniel Socialist landmarks (1952), 22 (Reel 3)
- LB 305 De Leon, Daniel and Job Harriman The socialist trade (1900), 23 (Reel 3)
- LB 327 Dyche, John A. Bolshevism in American labor union (1926), 24 (Reel 3)
- LB 335 Fairley, Lincoln The company union in plan and practice (1936), 25 (Reel 3)
- LB 337 Feldman, Herman Survey of research in the field of the industrial (1928), 26 (Reel 3)
- LB 338 Feller, Alexander and Jacob E. Hurwitz How to deal with organized labor (1937), 27 (Reel 3)
- LB 340 Williams, Whiting Mainsprings of men (1925), 28 (Reel 3)
- LB 343 MacDonald, Lois The worker and government (1935), 29 (Reel 3)
- LB 343 Supplement, 30 (Reel 3)
- LB 344 Miller, Glenn W. American labor and the government (1948), 31 (Reel 3)
- LB 345 Rawlins, William De V.,. A cross section of American opinion on the need for regulation (1937), 32 (Reel 3)
- LB 350 Taylor, Washington I. Employer's liability to their workmen for accidents (1889), 33 (Reel 3)
- LB 356 Frey, John P. The labor injunction (1923), 34 (Reel 3)
- LB 357 Johnsen, Julia E. Trade unions and the anti-trust laws (1940), 35 (Reel 3)
- LB 358 Mariano, John H. The Busch jewelry stores labor injunction (1940), 36 (Reel 3)
- LB 362 National Consumers' League. The Supreme Court and minimum wage legislation (1925), 37 (Reel 3)
- LB 369 Wood, Clement Don't tread on me (1928), 38 (Reel 3)
- LB 367 Seidenberg, Jacob The labor injunction in New York City, (1935-1950), 1 (Reel 4)
- LB 368 Teller, Ludwig The law governing labor disputes and collective bargaining 3 volumes (1940) (v.1), 2 (Reel 4)
- LB 368 Teller, Ludwig The law governing labor disputes and collective bargaining 3 volumes (1940) (v.2 and 3), 3 (Reel 4)
- LB 371 Bow, Frank T. Independent labor organizations (1940), 4 (Reel 4)
- LB 372 Brown, Emily C. National labor policy (1950), 5 (Reel 4)
- LB 374 Garland, Jasper V. Federal regulation of labor unions. (1941), 6 (Reel 4)
- LB 375 Johnsen, Julia E. Compulsory Federal arbitration of labor disputes (1947), 7 (Reel 4)
- LB 378 Lovestone, Jay The government: strikebreaker. (1923), 8 (Reel 4)
- LB 380 Sheldon, Horace E. Union security and the Taft-Hartley Act in the Buffalo area (1949), 9 (Reel 4)
- LB 384 Industrial Workers of the World The lumber industry and its workers (1921), 10 (Reel 4)
- LB 389 Archibald, Hugh The four hour day in coal (1922), 11 (Reel 4)
- LB 394 Bruere, Robert W. The coming of coal (1922), 12 (Reel 4)
- LB 398 Gilfillan, Harriet Woodbridge I went to pit college (1934), 13 (Reel 4)
- LB 400 Hudson, Harriet D. The progressive mine workers of America (1952), 14 (Reel 4)
- LB 401 Hunt, Edward E. What the coal commission found (1925), 15 (Reel 4)
- LB 407 National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners Harlan miners speak (1932), 16 (Reel 4)
- LB 409 Parker, Glen L. The Coal industry (1940), 17 (Reel 4)
- LB 410 Rochester, Anna Labor and coal (1931), 18 (Reel 4)
- LB 413 Simpson, Alexander G. The life of a miner in two hemispheres (1903), 19 (Reel 4)
- LB 415 Sulzberger, Cyrus L. Sit down with John L. Lewis (1938), 20 (Reel 4)
- LB 416 United Mine Workers of America John L. Lewis and the International Union (1952), 21 (Reel 4)
- LB 417 Van Kleeck, Mary Miners and management (1934), 22 (Reel 4)
- LB 422 Davidson, Lallah S. South of Joplin (1939), 23 (Reel 4)
- LB 430 Zausner, Philip Unvarnished (1941), 24 (Reel 4)
- LB 431 Belsky, Joseph I, the union (1952), 25 (Reel 4)
- LB 433 U. S. Works Progress Administration. Cigar Makers: after the lay-off. (1937), 26 (Reel 4)
- LB 435 Dunn, Robert W. and Jack Hardy Labor and textiles: a study of cotton (1931), 27 (Reel 4)
- LB 440 Phillips, Edward L. Collective bargaining and craft unions (1950), 28 (Reel 4)
- LB 442 Selekman, Benjamin M. Sharing management with the workers (1924), 29 (Reel 4)
- LB 444 Taylor, George W. The full-fashioned hosiery worker (1931), 30 (Reel 4)
- LB 445 U.S. Work Project Admin. Labor and the shutdown of the Amoskeag textile mills (1939), 31 (Reel 4)
- LB 446 Vorse, Mary H. Strike (1930), 32 (Reel 4)
- LB 448 Bookbinder, Hyman H. To promote(1950), 33 (Reel 4)
- LB 452 Hardman, J.B.S. and Len Giovannitti Sidney Hilman: labor statesman ( 1948), 34 (Reel 4)
- LB 453 Hardman, J.B.S. The Amalgamated today and tomorrow (1939), 35 (Reel 4)
- LB 451 Carsel, Wilfred A history of the Chicago Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (1940), 1 (Reel 5)
- LB 454 Hardman, J.B. S. The book of the Amalgamated in New York, 1914-1940 (1940), 2 (Reel 5)
- LB 455 Hardy, Jack [Dale Zysman, pseud.] The clothing workers (1935), 3 (Reel 5)
- LB 456 Haskel, Harry A leader of the garment workers (1950), 4 (Reel 5)
- LB 457 Howard, Earl D. The Hart, Schaffner and Marx labor agreement (1920), 5 (Reel 5)
- LB 459 LaMar, Elden The Clothing Workers in Philadelphia (1940), 6 (Reel 5)
- LB 460 Lewis, Marx Max Zaritsky at fifty (1935), 7 (Reel 5)
- LB 462 Oneal, James A history of the Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 (1927), 8 (Reel 5)
- LB 464 Robinson, Donald B. Spotlight on a union (1948), 9 (Reel 5)
- LB 465 Rogoff, Abraham M. Formative years of the Jewish labor movement (1945), 10 (Reel 5)
- LB 470 Women's Trade Union League of Chicago. Official report of the strike (1911), 11 (Reel 5)
- LB 472 -- Foner, Philip S. The Fur and Leather Workers Union (1950), 12 (Reel 5)
- LB 477 Horowitz, Daniel Labor relations in the petroleum industry (1937), 13 (Reel 5)
- LB 490 History of the Westinghouse Strike (1914), 14 (Reel 5)
- LB 495 McBride, Roberta Labor relations in the automobile industry (1950), 15 (Reel 5)
- LB 497 Reuther, Walter P. Purchasing power for prosperity (1945), 16 (Reel 5)
- LB 500 Bradley, Walter F. An industrial war (1923), 17 (Reel 5)
- LB 504 Estes, George Railway employees united (1931), 18 (Reel 5)
- LB 519 Eliel, Paul The waterfront and general strikes (1934), 19 (Reel 5)
- LB 521 Keller, Marvel Decasualization of longshore work in San Francisco (1939), 20 (Reel 5)
- LB 527 Ryan, Paul W. [Mike Quin, pseud.] On the drumhead (1948), 21 (Reel 5)
- LB 533 Walker, Charles R. American city:: a rank-and-file history (1937), 22 (Reel 5)
- LB 546 Cabe, J. Carl Foremen's unions (1947), 23 (Reel 5)